Cummings, E.E. (Edward Estlin), 1894-1962. Letters to Alfred Rice (MS Am 1892.16): Guide.
Letters to Alfred Rice,
1949-1961.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 1892.16
Cummings, E.E. (Edward Estlin), 1894-1962.
1 box (.5 linear ft.)
Letters from American poet E. E. Cummings to Alfred Rice.
*77M-50
Gift of Mr. Alfred Rice, 40 West 55th Street New York, New York 10019; received: 1978 May.
Cummings was an American poet.
Arranged alphabetically.
Letters mostly address the dispute over the title of Cummings' collection of poetry entitled Xaipe. He wrote to Rice explaining the pressures he felt from the editor Vaudrin. Baumgarten worked at Brandt and Brandt, and Vandrin at Oxford University Press. Cummings also wrote about problems over the inheritance of land from his mother. Several letters dispute Cummings' title to the land, and there is also a hand-drawn map of the land in question.
- Baumgarten, Bernice. T.L.s. to Edward Estlin Cummings; New York, 8 Sep 1949., (1); 1s. (1p.)
- Cummings, Edward Estlin, 1894-1962. T.L. (carbon copy) to Bernice Baumgarten; Silver Lake, 11 Sep 1949., (2); 1s. (1p.)
  With TS. (carbon copy) enclosure: 1s. (1p.)
- Cummings, Edward Estlin, 1894-1962. 7 letters to Alfred Rice:, (3-9)
  - T.L.s.; Silver Lake, 26 Aug 1949., (3); 1s. (1p.)
  - T.L.s.; same, 9 Sep 1949., (4); 1s. (1p.)
  - T.L.s.; same, 25 Sep 1949., (5); 1s. (1p.)
  - T.L.s.; same, 3 Sep 1953., (6); 2s. (2p.)
    With TS.D. (copy) of a deed by Rebecca Haswell (Clarke) Cummings. 1s. (1p.) With T.L.s. (carbon copy) from Edward Estlin Cummings to Marvin Fallgatter; same, 2 Jul 1953. 1s. (1p.) With T.L.s. from Marvin Fallgatter to Edward Estlin Cummings; Piedmont, 12 Jul 1953. 2s. (2p.) With T.L. (carbon copy) from Edward Estlin Cummings to Marvin Fallgatter; Silver Lake, 18 Jul 1953. 1s. (1p.) With T.L. (carbon copy) from Edward Estlin Cummings to Charles O. Dahl; same, 17 Aug 1953. 1s. (1p.) With MS. map: 1s. (1p.)
  - T.L.s.; same, 25 Sep 1953., (7); 1s. (1p.)
  - T.L.s.; same, 4 Oct 1953., (8); 1s. (1p.)
  - T.L.s.; [n.p.] 14 Apr 1961., (9); 1s. (1p.)
- Cummings, Edward Estlin, 1894-1962. 2 letters to Philip Vaudrin:, (10-11)
  - T.L. (carbon copy); Silver Lake, 17 Aug 1949., (10); 1s. (1p.)
  - T.L.s. (carbon copy); same, 9 Sep 1949., (11); 1s. (1p.)
- Rice, Alfred. T.L. (carbon copy) to Edward Estlin Cummings; [New York] 7 Sep 1949., (12); 1s. (1p.)
- Vaudrin, Philip. 2 letters to Edward Estlin Cummings:, (13-14)
  - T.L.s.; New York, 16 Aug 1949., (13); 1s. (1p.)
  - T.L.s.; same, 23 Aug 1949., (14); 1s. (1p.)